Guide to the Wartime at Duke Reference Collection, 1917-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
Wartime at Duke Reference collection 1917-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
0.4 linear feet Extent: approx. 400 Items
The Wartime at Duke Reference Collection contains files of publications, memoranda, reports, clippings, and other materials about the effects of war on the University and the University's contributions to war efforts. This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
RL.01936
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Wartime at Duke Reference Collection was compiled by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
Collection Overview
The Wartime at Duke Reference Collection contains material about the effects of war on the University and the University's contributions to war efforts. The collection include publications of the University and other organizations, reports, memoranda, notices, programs and announcements, flyers, clippings, and other material. Other organizations represented include the American Council on Education and American Women's Voluntary Services, Inc.
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - World War I (Box 1)
  - World War I - Student Army Training Corps
  - American Women's Voluntary Services, Inc., 1941-1942
  - Campus ceremonies, 1942-1945
  - Diploma: Honorable discharge from the University… [circa 1942-1945]
  - Duke University Civilian Public Services Unit 61, 1944
  - Duke University War Advisory Council, 1942
  - Duke University. Printed matter, 1941-1945
  - Duke University. Summaries of wartime activities of academic units and faculty, 1949
  - Navy V-12 Program, 1943-
  - Navy-Marine V-12 Program. 50th Anniversary, 1993
  - Navy V-12 Program / James G. Schneider, 1987 (extracts)
  - Printed matter, other organizations
  - War Service Opportunities for College and University Students / American Council on Education, 1942
  - World War II at Duke, miscellany
  - Writings and reminiscences